我们将再次查看递归Newton-Euler算法的结果。但
We're going to look at the results of the recursive Newton-Euler algorithm again. But
这一次，我们将使用MATLAB的计算机代数象征性地进行操作
this time, we're going to do the operations symbolically using MATLAB’s computer algebra
能力。我们要做的第一件事就是带来
capability. The first thing we are going to do is to bring
在两个链接机器人的模型中，这是带有后缀sym的mdl_twolink来指示
in a model of the two link robot, that’s the mdl_twolink with a suffix sym to indicate
它是一个象征性的模型。再一次，我们在我们的网站中创建了一个串行链接对象
that it is a symbolic model. And once again, we have a serial link object created in our
工作空间称为twolink。
workspace called twolink.
因为我将使用符号而不是数字，我需要实际定义我的
Because I am going to work with symbols rather than numbers, I need to actually define my
变量提前。所以，我将定义一个名为Q1和Q2的符号变量。和
variables in advance. So, I'm going to define a symbolic variable called Q1 and Q2. And
Q1D和Q2D表示关节1和关节2的速度，Q1DD表示加速度
Q1D and Q2D to represent the velocity of joints 1 and joint 2 and Q1DD to represent the acceleration
关节1和关节2的加速度。
of joint 1 and the acceleration of joint 2.
现在我已经拥有了，我可以像上次那样使用rne方法，我将要通过
Now that I have that, I can use the rne method just as I did last time and I'm going to pass
在作为符号变量Q1和Q2的关节角度中。我要传球了
in the joint angles which are the symbolic variables Q1 and Q2. I am going to pass in
作为符号变量Q1D和Q2D的联合速度，我将要通过
the, joint velocities which are the symbolic variables Q1D and Q2D and I'm going to pass
在关节加速度的符号变量中，即Q1DD和Q2DD。
in the symbolic variables for the joint acceleration which is Q1DD and Q2DD.
并且，我将把它保存到一个名为tau的变量中。我记得这样做。这里
And, I'm going to save this into a variable called tau. Do that while I remember. Here
我们去。这是结果。所以，如果我看一下正在起作用的扭矩
we go. Here is the result. So, if I look at the torque that is acting
在第一个关节，这里我们有一个扭矩的象征性表达，它是一个非常
on the first joint, here we have a symbolic expression for that torque and it is a very
长而复杂的表达。我们可以看到有许多运动学参数
long and complex expression. We can see that there are a number of kinematic parameters
在这里像A1和A2。我们可以看到有联合加速度，关节速度。我们
in here like A1 and A2. We can see there are joint accelerations, joint velocities. We
可以看到G，重力加速度有三角项。有联合
can see G, the gravitational acceleration there are trigonometric terms. There are joint
群众。有各种各样的东西。这是一个非常漫长而复杂的表达
masses. There is all sorts of stuff. It is a very long and very complicated expression
用于作用在我们的简单双连杆机器人的关节1上的扭矩。
for the torque acting on Joint 1 of our simple two link robot.
作用于关节2的扭矩，即肘关节机器人，是一种更简洁的表达方式。
The torque acting on Joint 2, that's the elbow joint robot, is a more concise expression.
作用在机器人的第二关节上的力和扭矩较小。我们可以
There are less complex forces and torques acting on the second joint of robot. We can
看到这个非常复杂的表达。想象一下六连杆机器人会是什么样子。
see this very complex expression. Imagine what it will be like for a six-link robot.
现在，我们可以分解和简化那些非常复杂的表达式
Now, it is possible to factorize and simplify those very complex expressions that we just
看着。特别是，如果我们以这种矩阵形式表达它。Tau是一个载体
looked at. In particular, if we express it in matrix form like this. Tau is a vector
施加的关节扭矩。Q，当然是我们的联合坐标，一般是联合
of the applied joint torques. Q, of course, is our joint coordinates, generally the joint
串联机械手的角度。Q点，关节速度，变化率
angles of the serial link manipulator. Q-dot, the joint velocities, the rates of change
关节坐标和Q点点是关节加速度。G是一个术语
of the joint coordinates and Q-dot-dot is the joint acceleration. G is a term which
表示由重力作用于机器人操纵器和重力引起的扭矩
represents the torque that's due to the gravity acting on the robot manipulator and gravity
仅是关节坐标Q的函数.M是惯性矩阵，它是一个函数
is a function only of the joint coordinates Q. M is the inertia matrix and it is a function
只有关节坐标乘以关节加速度。
only of the joint coordinates multiply by the joint accelerations.
这为我们提供了加速串行链接机械手所需的扭矩。C
This gives us the torque that's required to accelerate our serial link manipulator. C
被称为科里奥利和向心术语，这代表陀螺仪和陀螺仪
is referred to as the Coriolis and centripetal term and this represents the gyroscopic and
由于其他机器人关节的旋转而作用于机器人关节的其他力。
other forces that act on the robot joints due to the rotation of other robot joints.